<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Fabian</title>
    <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew Fabian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 14:29:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Personhood</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/about_me-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/about_me-copy/</guid>
      <description>Corporate Personhood is the concept that corporate entities should be extended many (but not all) of the same rights that the constitution grants to individuals, on the basis that a corporation is simply a collection of like minded individuals. But as Kate Cox writes in “How Corporations Got The Same Rights As People (But Don’t Ever Go To Jail),” “[C]orporations are not actually living, breathing, physical beings. They cannot go to jail, they cannot lose their lives, and they do not think or feel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Personhood</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/corporate_personhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/corporate_personhood/</guid>
      <description>Corporate Personhood is the concept that corporate entities should be extended many (but not all) of the same rights that the constitution grants to individuals, on the basis that a corporation is simply a collection of like minded individuals. But as Kate Cox writes in “How Corporations Got The Same Rights As People (But Don’t Ever Go To Jail),” “[C]orporations are not actually living, breathing, physical beings. They cannot go to jail, they cannot lose their lives, and they do not think or feel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brittany Wenger</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/brittany_wenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 14:29:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/brittany_wenger/</guid>
      <description>I collaborated with Monica Fallon to create this poster.
My reflection on women in STEM can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking into STEM</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/breaking_into_stem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/breaking_into_stem/</guid>
      <description>It is challenging for women to break into STEM fields. STEM is dominated by the &amp;ldquo;white male.&amp;rdquo; I remember walking into one of my first engineering specific classes, looking around the room of 22 people, and realizing that only 3 of the 22 people were either a woman or a minority. That type of ratio doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen by accident. There are a few reasons commonly cited for this disparity; STEM jobs offer less flexibility for family, there are a lack of female role models, and gender sterotypes influence preferences at a young age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Surveillance in a Technological World</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/government_surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 23:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/government_surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Long before the technological age, Benjamin Franklin said, &amp;ldquo;Those who would give up essential Liberty, to purchase a little temporary Safety, deserve neither Liberty nor Safety.&amp;rdquo; In other words, someone who sacrifices their privacy for their security deserves none. A hot button issue at the moment is whether tech companies should purposely weaken their encryption and security in order to provide government the opportunity to seize data and information related to crime or terror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chelsea Manning: Hero or Traitor?</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/chelsea_manning_hero_or_traitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/chelsea_manning_hero_or_traitor/</guid>
      <description>Chelsea Manning’s story is filled with nuance. It isn’t easy to claim an informed opinion and at the same time declare her actions completely moral or completely immoral. When Chelsea Manning leaked classified information to WikiLeaks, she may have thought she was doing the right thing. Maybe she didn’t think that, and wanted attention or approval. I think that it’s important to remove speculative motive in order to understand the action and results of the action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codes of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/codes_of_conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/codes_of_conduct/</guid>
      <description>My Kindergarten classroom had a poster displayed on the wall, outlining a Code of Conduct (of sorts) for the classroom. It read:
“Always keep your hands and feet to yourself.”
That was it. I’m sure there were rules about sharing and being kind and raising your hand to talk, but there was only one rule that was prominently displayed. When students broke that rule, it was easy for my teacher to point at the poster on the wall to provide reasoning on why the students shouldn’t have acted in the way they did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Work</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/why_we_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 23:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/why_we_work/</guid>
      <description>Having it all is a concept that society suggests everyone should strive to achieve. Your career should be rewarding. Your free time spent with your family. Promotions should be plentiful. Work-life balance a non-issue. Personally, I don’t think (most) men or women can have it all, and I don’t think they need to, either.
One of the key objectives on the quest to “have it all” is a fulfilling career. Depending on the person, a fulfilling career may include management or leadership roles, rapid advancement, and passion for one’s work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Interview Process</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/interview_process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 23:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/interview_process/</guid>
      <description>As a sophomore, when I was still studying Electrical Engineering, I went to the Career Fair with a list of ten companies in my pocket. My reasons for wanting to talk to these companies varied. Some were working on interesting projects, some were close to home, and a few were picked just because they said they had openings for Electrical Engineering internships. A week after I spoke with people at each of the companies and turned in applications online, a manager at Company X emailed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Computing Industy&#39;s Impact on Income Inequality</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/income_inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/income_inequality/</guid>
      <description>Does the computing industry have an obligation to address social and political issues? Absolutely not. An industry has no obligations, as it is a term used to refer to a branch of companies with similar products. The companies that make up the computing industry likewise have no obligation other than to make their shareholders money. If MegaCorp or BigBusiness can make the most money by ignoring or even flying in the face of sociopolitical issues, I have little doubt that we would see policies in place that accomplish just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming is not a Super-Power</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/programming_is_not_a_superpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 23:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/programming_is_not_a_superpower/</guid>
      <description>Karlie Kloss claims that coding is &amp;ldquo;a weapon, it&amp;rsquo;s like a super-power, it&amp;rsquo;s better than a super-power.&amp;rdquo; While I would agree that programming can be used as a weapon and that it can produce results more powerful than any super-power, I would not agree that programming in and of itself is a super-power. If something is a super-power, there must be something about that ability that is inherently limiting. For example, Superman has the ability to fly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 14:29:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mdf730.github.io/ethicsblog/post/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Matthew Fabian, and I am a senior studying Computer Engineering with a minor in Engineering Corporate Practice. I&amp;rsquo;m from sunny Buffalo, NY originally, and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past four years living in Alumni Hall. I came to Notre Dame with the intention of studying Electrical Engineering, but changed majors a few days into my junior year. As a fun side effect of that, I&amp;rsquo;ll be one of the first people to graduate following the new CSE curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>